4 Cavill Court, Vermont South, VIC 3133 0413 121 437 - samhwang21121994@gmail.com au.linkedin.com/in/samhwang2112

Summary

With skills in PHP Web Development and IT Technical Support, I believe I can contribute to ensuring operational effectiveness of the organization. To new opportunities I bring my strong back-end development and troubleshooting skills as well as a problem-solver attitude and the ability to work well in a fast-paced environment under pressure. I believe my experience makes me a good fit for the organization undertaking the role.

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology

October 2012 – December 2015

RMIT University (Vietnam & Melbourne Campus)

Professional Year Program in Computer Science

October 2016 – October 2017

Navitas Professionals, Melbourne

Professional Experience

PHP Developer Intern Psych Press

June 2017 – September 2017

Level 6, 140 Queen Street, Melbourne, VIC 3000

- Responsible for building various internal web applications and projects under close collaboration with the company's marketing/psychology team.
- Provided software maintenance for existing customer's projects, as well as hardware support for the company as a whole, including and not limited to optimizing older components between existing machines and planning and building new workstations for the developing team.

Contract Web Developer Mint and Co. Accessories (Mint&Co.)

October 2015 – February 2016

Collins Street, Melbourne, VIC 3000

- Responsible for designing and developing the e-commerce site for Mint&Co. from the ground up, including scouting for hosts and finding the most suitable technologies at the lowest cost.
- Provided regular maintenance of the site, including both site maintenance and server-side maintenance.
- Ensured the connectivity to the server to minimize loss of sales.
- Screen shots of the project: https://www.behance.net/gallery/33362005/Mint-and-Co-Accessories-e-commerce-site

Web Developer Right Left Communication

September 2014 - January 2015

21 Gladstone Street, Moonee Ponds, VIC 3039

- Provided 24-hour support on weekdays for clients' enquiries and ensuring the best result for the customer.

- Responsible creating and managing websites to cater to the customers' requirements and needs.

- Resolved and provided solutions for IT related queries either to clients or to internal staff in a 2-business-day time frame, including database management for each project.

Skills Summary

Technical skills

Database skills

- Software Development and Familiar with the procedures of the Software Development Lifecycle (including Agile methodologies) and collaborations in open-source projects.
 - Proficient in developing with PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript (¡Query), Python and Ruby.
 - Basic knowledge of widely known CMSs and frameworks (Wordpress, Joomla, and CodeIgniter).
 - Version control via Git i.e. in Terminal or PowerShell.
 - Basic knowledge of setting up Apache and IIS servers.
 - Relational database design and queries using MySQL and MS SQL.
 - Familiar with project management tools (JIRA, Trello, Asana.)

Other Technical Skills

- Familiar in using, navigating and diagnosing problems with multiple desktop operating systems, including Windows, Mac OS X, Linux, as well as iOS and Android mobile devices.
- Proficient in using MS Office Suite (Word, Excel and PowerPoint) and similar Google Drive collaboration tools (Docs, Sheets and Slides) along with media editing tools such as Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop and Premiere).
- Personal computer maintenance and hardware troubleshooting skills. alongside planning and building new machines.

Soft skills – Personal qualities

- Professional fluency in English and native fluency in Vietnamese.
- Demonstrated capability of working efficiently both as an individual and as a member of a team, especially in a fast-paced environment and in open-sourced projects.
- Committed to learning and improving myself through work and for work.
- Currently on Permanent Residence VISA Subclass 189 with full working rights.